ADEKALU, ADEDAYO ADEKITAN

PROFILE

A vibrant engineer with a strong desire to gain transversal and technical skills needed to thrive in the global economy, gain new experiences, embrace different cultures and interested in applying analytical and critical thinking skills to assess and interpret business metrics.

PERSONAL DATA

Date of Birth: 6th January, 1998

Place of Birth: Lagos Marital Status: Single

Address: Block 125 flat 5 Ijaye housing estate Ogba Lagos.

Phone No.: +234 8034763331

E-Mail Address: <u>dayoadekalu@gmail.com</u>

EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION ATTENDED

University of Lagos, Akoka Lagos. January 2014- November 2018

Queens College, Yaba, Lagos September 2010 - June 2013

QUALIFICATIONS OBTAINED

BSc (Hons). Mechanical Engineering November 2018

Graduated with a second-class upper division degree with a final grade point average of 3.93

West African Secondary School Certificate Examination June 2013

WORK EXPERIENCE

STAG ENGINEERING NIGERIA LIMITED, AJAO ESTATE, LAGOS STATE May 2017 - October 2017

Worked as an engineering intern

Conducted cost effectiveness assessments of repair versus overhaul of diesel engines via technical assessments, preparation of job cards, costing of repair procedure.

Conducted repair of diesel engines, recalibration of fuel injectors and general servicing of stationary diesel engines.

REMO-NORTH LOCAL GOVERNMENT, ISARA-REMO OGUN STATE.

April 2019 - March 2020

Served in the Department of Works as a trainee engineer

Cost estimation for small scale local government projects, supervision of project sites, and inspection of local government assets in current use.

HAMOYE

August 2020- December 2020.

Gained experience on the utilization of python to develop prediction models, data visualization, data cleaning and computer vision

LEITUNG GATE LIMITED FADEYI, LAGOS STATE

September 2020 - Present

Process analyst/Management system Auditor

Conducted internal audits and gap assessments based on ISO 9001, ISO 14001 and ISO 45001 standards, developed client specific risk assessment methodologies, Developed and implemented data collection systems, Analysed process performance data using statistical techniques, developed process improvement pathways

SKILLS

- 1. Dynamic and quick in grasping new concepts and software utilization techniques with confidence.
- 2. Advanced Proficiency in Microsoft office suite (word, excel, PowerPoint) and quick adaptability to new software requirements.
- 3. Advanced proficiency in python for data analysis, visualization and modelling using various libraries (pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, scikit learn, jupyter notebook and TensorFlow).
- 4. Proficiency in Tableau and Power BI for data visualization
- 5. Intermediate level SQL proficiency
- 6. Good people skills and strong analytical mind with the ability to work effectively in a team.
- 7. Effective oral and written communication skills.
- 8. Initiative-taking with strong ability to work under pressure.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- 1. Data exploration of Nigerian datasets
- 2. Demonstration of classification and regression models used in popular datasets such as the titanic datasets and the Boston house price data set.

Portfolio Website: https://vervainalthor.github.io/Adekalu portfolio/

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Served as the secretary for the Gender Vanguard Community Development Service group Remo North chapter. The activities of the group involved the education of teenagers and Adults on societal issues such as child marriage and Gender-based violence.

April 2019 -February 2020.

Four- t i m e Gold Medalist on the 100m race and two- t i m e silver medalist on the 200m race of the annual University of Lagos Engineering Games (ULES) with a recognition as the fastest female athlete in the faculty. **2014 -2018**.

CORE VALUES

Integrity, resilience and competence

HOBBIES

Reading fiction and Writing.

REFEREES (Available on request)